Sasha Prokhorenko

+380 (98) 210 27 51 | djminikin@gmail.com | http://minikin.me

Professional Summary

Forward thinking & awarded iOS & IoT software engineer
2 years of experience in iOS development
5 years of development & delivery IoT projects for high-profile clients
Able to meet tight deadlines and delivers superior performance
Passionate about learning and trying new technologies

Experience

IOS SOFTWARE ENGINEER, SELF-EMPLOYED - 2014-PRESENT

- iOS applications development with Swift, UIKit, CoreLocation, MapKit, MapBox, REST API's integration, Fabric, Travis,
- Launched & developed iOS application "Kebab O'Clock" with extensive use of NSOperations, Realm & custom collectionView layouts,
- Backend infrastructure development and integration with IBM Bluemix, Firebase and Parse.

RESEARCH & DEVELOPMENT DIRECTOR, AIMBULANCE - 2010-PRESENT

Awarded the most effective digital agency in Ukraine (2015, 2012, 2011).

- Delivered & developed IoT projects (software & hardware) from scratch for big clients,
- Responsible for R&D that expanded company technologies,
- Optimised web production process & minimised risks,
- Supervised project production processes,
- Coordinating and monitoring work of software developers and third parties,
- Technical consulting.

PROJECT MANAGER, BRAINBERRY - 2007-2010

Digital agency which provides complex digital campaigns for high-profile clients & launched a few start-ups.

- Project management,
- Delivered multiple websites for clients,
- Launched several web start-ups,
- Coordinating and monitoring work of software developers and third parties,
- UX design development and prototyping,
- Quality assurance.

Skills

Swift - iOS SDK - Xcode - CocoaPods - Realm - IoT - Python - REST - JSON - Arduino - RaspberryPi - JavaScript - CSS - HTML - WebSocket - Ubuntu/Debian - Git -Travis/CircleCI - Sketch

Education

National Mining University, Dnipropetrovsk (Ukraine) – Master of Engineering (M.Eng.), 2002 - Electrical Engineering Technologies/Technicians.